DAN KLEIN: You've all heard
of hill climbing.
Maybe not in this particular context,
but the general idea.
You've all heard of it.
It's a simple general idea.
You start somewhere and then you do
the following over and over again.
Look in your local neighborhood and
move to the best neighboring state
according to some value function.
If there are no neighbors better than
where you are right now, then you're
standing on the top of
a hill, and you quit.
You say, I cannot locally
improve this hypothesis.
So what's bad about this approach?
Is it complete?
Nope.
So for example, we go up, we go up, we
go up, and all of the sudden, we have
a robot that standing here at the top
of the hill and it says there's no
local step I can take
to improve things.
And maybe you imagine the robot is
glancing wistfully at this wonderful
goal up here, but in fact, that's
not how local search works.
All you know about the problem is that,
from where you are, everything
looks downhill, so you stop.
And you might stop at
a very bad place.
So it's not complete.
It's not optimal.
So what's actually good about this?
What's good about it is you can start
anywhere, you can do the best you can,
and there are a wide range of problems
in the real world where any solution
will work, and you'd like to make it as
good as possible and you know you
can't get to the optimal solution, but
you might as well start somewhere and
make it as good as you can.
So here's a diagram that I think's very
important to have in your head.
This is that same mountain in essence
where the important terms here are,
somewhere there is a global maximum.
That is the best you can do according
to your objective function.
Now, you don't know necessarily what the
value of the global optimum is, if
you're there, you don't even know you're
there, and if you're not there,
you also don't know that
you're not there.
So in general, all you know is that
you are at some local maximum.
So when you find that everything around
you is worse, than you're at
some local maximum.
Is it the global maximum?
Maybe, in general, you
won't even know.
Is it even vaguely good?
No, right?
It could be that you are down here
on the tiniest little blip,
and you don't know.
These are problems.
There are other cases where
things get flat.
And when things are flat, maybe they're
flat because there's a local
plateau, or maybe they're flat just
because you're at a region where
you've got to move sideways
for a while before you can
start going up again.
This is difficult because these regions
that are flat, you have no
guidance about whether you're going left
or right or what, and you don't
really know whether there
even is an up.
So not only are they hard to navigate,
but you can't tell these two apart.
In general, when you're at a current
state, if there's a way to go up, you
know what that is.
So that's not really the problem
with local search.
Making progress isn't the problem.
The problem is, once you get to
a local optimum, you don't
know what to do next.
Now, there are ideas
that are powerful.
One of the ideas is simply just start
this thing a bunch of times, and if
you're in an absolutely horrible
state, maybe one of the
restarts does better.
But of course, the more restarts you
do, the more time it takes, and you
might need a massive number restarts to
make any progress if this is some
exponential space, as
they typically are.